In an ordinary place, he found the one person to make his life extraordinary.
Finding Forrester is a drama, history film directed by Gus Van Sant.
Gus Van Sant tells the story of a young African American man named Jamal who
confronts his talents while living on the streets of the Bronx.
He accidentally runs into an old writer named Forrester
who discovers his passion for writing.
With help from his new mentor Jamal receives a scholarship to a private school.
William Forrester, played by Sean Connery.
Jamal Wallace, played by Rob Brown.
Robert Crawford, played by F. Murray Abraham.
Claire Spence, played by Anna Paquin.
Kenzo, played by Damany Mathis.
Terrell Wallace, played by Busta Rhymes.
Finding Forrester is a 2000 American drama film directed
by Gus Van Sant and written by Mike Rich.
In the film, a teenager, Jamal Wallace (Rob Brown), is invited
to attend a prestigious private high school.
By chance, Jamal befriends a reclusive writer, William Forrester (Sean Connery), through
whom he refines his talent for writing and comes to terms with his identity.
Anna Paquin, F.
Murray Abraham, Michael Pitt, Glenn Fitzgerald, April Grace, Busta
Rhymes, and Charles Bernstein star in supporting roles.
Although the film is not based on a true story, film critics have compared
the character portrayed by Connery with real-life writer J.
Connery later acknowledged that the inspiration
for his role was indeed Salinger.
The film explores themes of dying and death, high school,
friendship, scholarship, sibling relationship.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.